<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Lex Nederbragt</title>
<link>https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/</link>
<atom:link href="https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Lex Nederbragt&#39;s personal website</description>
<generator>quarto-1.8.27</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Artificial, or simulated intelligence?</title>
  <link>https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/2026-02-03-simulated_intelligence/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>I am very much interested in Artificial Intelligence (AI), both in general, and in what it means for (higher) education. My focus is mostly on Generative AI, such as Large Language Models (LLMs), Image generation etc. I am mostly trying out how much I can get done using tools that my university has enabled me to use. These include the University of Oslo’s own wrapper around OpenAI’s ChatGPT (gpt.uio.no), and Google’s NotebookLM. I also have obtained API access to OpenAI’s GPT models, provided by the university through the Microsoft Azure platform. I use this to write code (with the help of the Roocode plugin for Visual Studio Code). I also use commercial platforms (Google Gemini, Google AI search, Perplexity, ChatGPT) but so far have no paid subscription to any of them<sup>1</sup>.</p>
<p>I hope to occasionally post some of my experiences, findings and opinions on this blog. Here is the first post!</p>
<p>An important aspect to understand when working with LLMs is that at a basic level, they are next-token predictors. A token here means a word, or part of a word. This means that given a set of tokens, for example, your question (prompt), LLMs use their model to predict possible next tokens, and choose one of the most likely ones. Based on all previous tokens, and the one just chosen, the model is then used to predict the next ones and choose one of these. There is some stochasticity here, so asking the same model the same question twice may in fact yield slightly different results.</p>
<p>Still, these next-token predictors turn out to be generating surprisingly well-written sentences. This is what makes them so useful.</p>
<section id="hallucinations---llms-dreaming-up-things" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="hallucinations---llms-dreaming-up-things">Hallucinations - LLMs dreaming up things</h2>
<p>Sometimes the model will go astray, especially if it is asked about something that is not in its training data (or that it cannot look up elsewhere). The result is plausible-looking wording that may be complete nonsense. This is what is usually called hallucinations.</p>
<p>In the spirit of the subtitle of this post: I think the word ‘hallucination’ is a misnomer. Hallucination is defined <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hallucination">on Wikipedia</a> as</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>[…] a perception in the absence of an external context stimulus that has the compelling sense of reality.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When hallucinating, one may see something (a perception) that isn’t really there.</p>
<p>LLMs generating plausible but nonsense text don’t perceive anything. Therefore, this phenomenon I’d rather call ‘Dreaming up things’, or ‘confabulation’. That latter term is defined, again <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confabulation">using Wikipedia</a>, as</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>[…] a memory error consisting of the production of fabricated, distorted, or misinterpreted memories about oneself or the world. […] Confabulation occurs when individuals mistakenly recall false information, without intending to deceive.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That last part, ‘without intending to deceive’ is important (if you’ll allow me a bit of anthropomorphism, as an LLM cannot really have intention - more on that below). Unfortunately, we are already stuck with the word hallucination.</p>
</section>
<section id="simulated-intelligence" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="simulated-intelligence">Simulated Intelligence</h2>
<p><img src="https://lexnederbragt.com/img/AI_simulated_intelligence.png" class="img-fluid"> Modified infographic generated by NotebookLM.</p>
<p>My main point with this post is that also the term ‘Artificial Intelligence’ could be said to be misleading. Writing this post was inspired by reading the White Paper by Tom Chatfield entitled “AI and the Future of Pedagogy” <sup>2</sup>. This White Paper makes many valuable points. Here, I’d like to focus on one of them.</p>
<p>I quote:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Within the space of a few years, it has become possible to simulate knowledge and understanding of almost any topic while possessing neither.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The use of the word “simulate” really resonated with me. If we consider the output of LLMs to be ‘Simulated Intelligence’, rather than “Artificial Intelligence”, that changes our perspective. It may look intelligent, but it is not real intelligence, it is <em>simulated</em>. Chatfield also writes about LLM’s ability to “simulate social interactions”. And “Modern generative AIs are all too adept at simulating emotion, empathy and interest.”</p>
<p>I think using this term may help a lot with interpreting the outputs from LLMs, and making use of them. If the ‘intelligence’ is simulated, one needs to look at it critically, because it may have weaknesses. It should not be used to replace one’s own intelligence. Intelligence simulated by a machine cannot have intentions. Looking at it this way may also help students apply it carefully so as to not diminish their learning.</p>
<p>Tom Chatfield is not the only, or even first one to use this word. A ‘quick’ Deep Research query with Gemini (through Google AI Studio) or Perplexity yields several others that have explicitly suggested using the term “Simulated Intelligence”<sup>3</sup>. But for me, this was the first time I came across this term.</p>
<p>I hope this may be a useful perspective for others as well.</p>
<p>Comments on this post are welcome on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/lexnederbragt_artificial-or-simulated-intelligence-new-activity-7424469867698749440-5tCQ">LinkedIn</a>.</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Except for the image, no generative artificial intelligence tools were used in the writring of this blogpost.↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Chatfield, T (2025). AI and the future of pedagogy (White Paper). London: Sage. doi: 10.4135/wp520172 https://www.sagepub.com/explore-our-content/white-papers/2025/11/03/ai-and-the-future-of-pedagogy↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>A good example is David Sherwood, “Artificial Intelligence or Simulated Intelligence?” https://cogscisol.com/artificial-intelligence-or-simulated-intelligence/.↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>AI</category>
  <category>genAI</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/2026-02-03-simulated_intelligence/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Scaling Participatory live coding in an undergraduate computational biology course</title>
  <link>https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/2020-04-02-scaling-live-coding/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>This post is about the course BIOS1100 - Introduction to Computational Modelling in the Biosciences, that I have taught at the University of Oslo, Norway since 2017. I describe why and how we incorporated participatory live coding (students ‘coding-along’ with an instructor) into the teaching, and what effects this technique has had on first-year bioscience students learning programming in Python.</p>
<section id="background" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="background">Background</h2>
<p>From 2017, the Biosciences bachelor study program have started to incorporate Computing in Science Education (<a href="https://www.mn.uio.no/ccse/english/about/aims-and-vision.html">CSE</a>) into the different subjects. As part of this effort, I develop and teach a new semester-long course “Introduction to Computational Modelling for the Biosciences”. The course teaches first-semester students Python programming and basic mathematical modelling. BIOS1100 is not a pure programming course, Python is taught so students can used it to implement simple mathematical models to address relevant biological questions.</p>
<p>In two earlier blog posts, I explained the <a href="https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/2017-03-08-a-new-1st-semester-bachelor-course-introduction-to-computational-modelling-for-the-biosciences/">rationale behind the course</a> and <a href="https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/2017-12-17-experiences-with-the-first-edition-of-introduction-to-computational-modelling-for-the-biosciences">how the first edition went</a>. In that latter post, I concluded that I needed to use Participatory Live Coding to teach students the basics of Python programming.</p>
</section>
<section id="what-is-participatory-live-coding" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="what-is-participatory-live-coding">What is Participatory live coding</h2>
<p>Participatory live coding is a technique where a teacher or instructor writes and narrates code out loud as they teach, and invites learners to join them by writing and executing the same code - they ‘code-along’ with the instructor. Benefits of participatory live coding are that it slows the instructor down, allows for making the thought process of programming explicit, activates the learners and shows them how to diagnose and correct mistakes.</p>
<p>Participatory live coding is the main teaching method in workshops organised by the global non-profit called <a href="https://carpentries.org">The Carpentries</a>, the umbrella organisation for Software Carpentry, Data Carpentry and Library Carpentry. As an active Carpentries instructor, I use this technique when teaching, for example, programming, the Unix shell or the use of the version control tool git.</p>
</section>
<section id="participatory-live-coding-and-bios1100" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="participatory-live-coding-and-bios1100">Participatory live coding and BIOS1100</h2>
<p>In the first edition of my BIOS1100 course, I initially did not want to use the technique as I thought it wouldn’t scale up to the 60 or 200 students in the room during group sessions, or lectures, respectively. But I ended up using participatory live coding in the latter part of the course to help students that struggled learning the programming part of the course. Based on the positive feedback from the students I then decided to implement participatory live coding as the main technique for teaching elementary Python concepts in BIOS1100 from then on.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-challenge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-challenge">The challenge</h2>
<p>How to teach using participatory live coding to large groups of students? Carpentries workshops have usually no more than 30 participants and a healthy helper-to-participant ratio (1 to 10 or better). In BIOS1100, students meet in groups of up to 60, or in lectures up to 200. An important aspect of live coding is keeping all learners engaged and not leaving anyone behind because they run into a problem. The challenge for BIOS1100 was how to make sure one student getting stuck not delaying all the others. Also, with a lecture and four four-hour group sessions each week, doing all the live coding myself would constitute an enormous workload - teaching in itself is tiring, and teaching using participatory live coding usually even more so.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-solution" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-solution">The solution</h2>
<p>The most important thing I did was to train several teaching assistants (graduate students with teaching duty as part of their PhD) in how to deliver a lesson using participatory live coding. I asked each one to prepare for this by assigning them the relevant parts of the <a href="https://carpentries.github.io/instructor-training/14-live/index.html">Carpentries instructor training materials</a>. I then had each of them do a live practice session in front of the others and myself, where they gave each other feedback.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://lexnederbragt.com/img/live-coding_bios1100_1.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>A teaching assistant doing participatory live coding with BIOS1100 students (photo by the author)</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>I also spent a lot of time carefully preparing lesson materials for the live coding sessions in advance. Teaching at this levels is done in Norwegian, so I (mostly) wrote this material in that language.</p>
<p>We used the University of Oslo’s JupyterHub, a cloud-based service enabling students to use Jupyter Notebooks, with any necessary packages pre-installed and an easy way for instructors to distrubute files to all students. This common infrastrucure meant no installation issues on student’s machine, and helped limit the kind of technical problems learners often run into.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-results" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-results">The results</h2>
<p>In the 2018 edition of BIOS1100, participatory live coding was used during the obligatory 4-hour group sessions. Students loved it! Teaching assistants reported back to me that they students had a much better foundation in basic Python. However, we used so much of the four hours available for each groups session for live coding that there was too little time left for the students to work on exercises on their own with the help of the teaching assistants.</p>
<p>For the 2019 edition I thus decided to use weekly 2-hour <em>non</em>-obligatory sessions with participatory live coding sessions for the foundational Python. These sessions were focussed on the coding-along part, with deliberately little time for exercises. In group sessions, live coding was still used for worked examples, to demonstrate things and to explain material that the students struggled with. This left enough time, usually at least 2 hours, for working-on-your-own on exercises in the classroom (discussing with each other and/or the teaching assistants).</p>
<p>The experience from the 2019 model was that a number of students that should have gone to the participatory live coding sessions didn’t attend them, as these were voluntary. But we kept the benefit of the students that did participate learning the material very well.</p>
<p>Surprisingly, having students fall behind was never a big issue. Teaching assistants present during the live coding sessions reported usually having very little to do in terms of helping students getting unstuck. This may have been due to the fact that everyone, student as well as instructor, used the same Jupyter environment. Students were otherwise very good asking the instructor doing the live coding for help when they lost track.</p>
<p>Although I tried it out a few times, so far I have decided against doing participatory live coding during lectures with all students together. It happened too easy that one or two students miss a vital piece of information and get stuck, but didn’t notify me and thus missed a section of the live coding.</p>
</section>
<section id="why-does-it-work" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="why-does-it-work">Why does it work?</h2>
<p>I have often asked myself what it is about the code-along style of teaching that makes it so successful for teaching programming and similar subjects to novices. I think part of the answer has to do with motivation and mindset. My students probably did not choose the Bioscience program at the University of Oslo because they wanted to learn Python programming. Yet, this is what they are taught from the very first semester. As for the people signing up for Carpentries workshops, many of them figured out that their research or career would benefit from learning computational skills. However, they also may think that learning to program is a scary thing and ‘not for them’.</p>
<p>The technique of participatory live coding is carefully guiding the learner through the early stages of learning programming. It is almost as if the instructor is hand-holding the learner and thereby lowering the barrier to get started. I have had BISO1100 students give me feedback that they overcame their fear of programming already after one live coding session. It suddenly wasn’t scary anymore! Proper research needs to be done to confirm these suspicions, but my hypothesis would be that learners with low confidence in their ability to learn programming at the start of a course benefit from the participatory live coding approach in that it helps them obtain a growth mindset towards learning programming.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-future" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-future">The future</h2>
<p>I may in the future may make the participatory live coding sessions obligatory, with exemptions for students with sufficient Python knowledge. Until then, I want to do a better job at ‘selling’ the sessions, ensuring that students who need them actually attend them.</p>
<p>Although we won’t be doing participatory live coding in lectures, I do want to experiment with non-participatory live coding, i.e.&nbsp;demonstrations and worked examples during those times all students are together with a teacher. The students like seeing their teachers program and there is value in spending time on going over exercises from the previous week or demonstrate code that helps address misconceptions.</p>
<p>Finally, I hope to convince others aiming to teach programming to audiences normally not having it as part of their studies (humanities! social sciences!) to adopt this method of teaching, at least in the beginning.</p>
<p>I am now confident that I have found a teaching model for BIOS1100, using participatory live coding, that enables us to focus on applying programming to what the BIOS1100 course really is about: an introduction to computational modelling of biological problems!</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>BIOS1100</category>
  <category>teaching</category>
  <category>live-coding</category>
  <guid>https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/2020-04-02-scaling-live-coding/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Announcing canvasCourseCli</title>
  <link>https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/2020-03-04-announcing-canvasCourseCli/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>I wrote a small command line tool (in Python) for retrieving, adding and updating content, pages and files exposed to students and teachers, for a Canvas course.</p>
<section id="motivation" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="motivation">Motivation</h2>
<p>At the University of Oslo, we started using Canvas a few years back. Writing content for the pages of a course is normally done through a web-interface. However, I am very fond of writing content for the web in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown">Markdown</a>. However, there is no option to write in Markdown directly in the Canvas web interface.<br>
I also like to keep my textfiles under version control. So, I needed a way to write course pages in Markdown, convert them to html and upload them to my Canvas course, ideally through the command line - another tool I am very fond of. Since I could not find such a tool, so I decided to write my own. After all, Canvas is <a href="https://github.com/instructure/canvas-lms/wiki">an open source project</a> and has an <a href="https://canvas.instructure.com/doc/api/index.html">API</a>!</p>
</section>
<section id="canvascoursecli" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="canvascoursecli">canvasCourseCli</h2>
<p>Thus was born <code>canvasCourseCli</code>. It uses the Canvas API through the Python package <a href="https://github.com/ucfopen/canvasapi">canvasapi</a>. Commands start with <code>canvasCourseCli</code> followed by one of the subcommands:</p>
<pre><code>list_files    -u URL                        List all files for a course on Canvas.
list_pages    -u URL                        List all pages for a course on Canvas.
tree          -u URL                        List all folders for a course on Canvas.
dump          -u URL                        Download all files and pages for a course on Canvas.
view_page     -u URL                        View the content of a page on Canvas.
add_page      -u URL -t TITLE -f HTML_FILE  Add a new page to Canvas.
create_folder -u URL                        Create a new folder on Canvas.
add_file      -u URL -f FILE_TO_SEND        Add a file to a folder on Canvas.
update_page   -u URL -f HTML_FILE           Update the content of a page on Canvas.
add_to_module -u URL -m MODULE_NAME         Add a page on Canvas to a module.</code></pre>
<p>For example, if you want to replace the content of an existing page with content of a file (in html format) on your computer, for an imaginary course that ‘lives’ at https://instance.instructure.com/courses/9999, you could run this command:</p>
<pre><code>canvasCourseCli update_page -u https://instance.instructure.com/courses/9999/pages/name-of-page -f file.html</code></pre>
<p>I hope to develop more subcommands in the future.</p>
</section>
<section id="how-i-use-it" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="how-i-use-it">How I use it</h2>
<ul>
<li>I write course pages in Markdown</li>
<li>convert them to html using <a href="https://pandoc.org">pandoc</a></li>
<li>upload or update them to Canvas using <code>canvasCourseCli</code></li>
<li>I use a Makefile and <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/make/">Gnu Make</a> to automate this process</li>
<li>I also automate uploading some of the files that I add to Canvas on a weekly basis through that Makefile</li>
</ul>
<p>All pages for the latest edition of my course ‘BIOS1100 - Introduction to Computational Modelling in the Biosciences’ are written in Markdown and updated on Canvas through <code>canvasCourseCli</code>, and many of the course’s files are added through it too. Feel free to view the results at <a href="https://uio.instructure.com/courses/20058">the Canvas page for this course</a>.</p>
</section>
<section id="what-about-the-canvas-data-cli-tool-canvasdatacli" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="what-about-the-canvas-data-cli-tool-canvasdatacli">What about the Canvas Data CLI Tool <code>canvasDataCli</code>?</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://community.canvaslms.com/docs/DOC-6600-how-to-use-the-canvas-data-cli-tool#jive_content_id_Overview">Canvas Data CLI Tool</a> is used to extract course data from the database. <code>canvasCourseCli</code> is meant to work with course pages and files.</p>
</section>
<section id="how-to-install-it" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="how-to-install-it">How to install it</h2>
<p>For now, <code>canvasCourseCli</code> is available through a GitHub repo at <a href="https://github.com/lexnederbragt/canvasCourseCli">https://github.com/lexnederbragt/canvasCourseCli</a>. Clone that repo, or <a href="https://github.com/lexnederbragt/canvasCourseCli/releases">download the code</a>, and make it available on your system. I hope to make it into a ‘proper’ Python package, installable through (for example) <code>pip</code>, as soon as I find time to figure out how to do that.</p>
<p>Further documentation can be found in the <a href="https://github.com/lexnederbragt/canvasCourseCli/blob/master/README.md#canvascoursecli">README file</a> of the repository.</p>
<section id="a-word-of-warning" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-word-of-warning">A word of warning</h3>
<p>I have not been able to test <code>canvasCourseCli</code> on any other Canvas (instructure) instance than the one provided by my university. I would appreciate feedback (through the <a href="https://github.com/lexnederbragt/canvasCourseCli/issues">issue</a> functionality of the Github repository) on <em>both</em> successful and failed attempts at using the tool for your course.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="whats-next" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="whats-next">What’s next</h2>
<p>I hope to add functionality and improve the code in the near future. There is a <a href="https://github.com/lexnederbragt/canvasCourseCli/blob/master/TODO.md">ToDo list</a> that has my thoughts and wishes for further development. I welcome contributions!</p>
</section>
<section id="a-note-on-teaching-programming-and-using-the-command-line" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-note-on-teaching-programming-and-using-the-command-line">A note on teaching, programming and using the command line</h2>
<p>I used to do a lot of command line based analysis on supercomputers. These days, I mostly teach programming to novices. However, as much as possible I try to use my ‘command line and programming skills’ for my teaching work. So</p>
<ul>
<li>I write course materials in Markdown or <a href="https://github.com/hplgit/doconce/wiki/manual">DocOnce</a> (another markup language)</li>
<li>have all text files under version control</li>
<li>convert to different formats through the command line</li>
<li>automated using <code>make</code> and Makefiles where possible</li>
<li>synchronize the files to Canvas with <code>canvasCourseCli</code></li>
</ul>
<p>Not only does this make me more efficient, I also find it a fun way to work (and it keeps my skills up to date)!</p>
<p>This is my first real piece of software that I deliberately wrote also for others to use. Pretty scary, actually! But I realized that if <code>canvasCourseCli</code> is useful to others, I may even get people interested in helping me to improve the tool!</p>
<p>Finally, when writing this program, and setting up the repository, I aimed to follow the recommendations we wrote in the <a href="https://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005510">Good enough practices in scientific computing</a> paper. I found that to be a very useful exercise!</p>
<p>Enjoy <code>canvasCourseCli</code> and, as I said, <a href="https://github.com/lexnederbragt/canvasCourseCli/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md">I welcome contributions</a>!</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>canvas</category>
  <category>teaching</category>
  <guid>https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/2020-03-04-announcing-canvasCourseCli/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>FWIW: abbreviations useful to know for reading posts on Twitter</title>
  <link>https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/2018-12-17-twitter-abbreviations/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>I may happend that you, like me, come across abbreviations when reading tweets that I have no idea of what they mean. I have collected the ones I see the most and that I either knew from before, or managed to figure out the meaning of, here. Feel free to add more in the comments!</p>
<table class="caption-top table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Abbreviation</th>
<th>Full meaning</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>AFAICR</td>
<td>As Far As I Can Remember</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>AFAICT</td>
<td>As Far As I Can Tell</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>AFAIK</td>
<td>As Far As I Know</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>AKA</td>
<td>Also Known As</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>DYK</td>
<td>Did (Do) You Know</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>FWIW</td>
<td>For What It’s Worth</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>ICYMI</td>
<td>In Case You Missed It</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>IIRC</td>
<td>If I Recall Correctly</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>IJK</td>
<td>I’m just kidding</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>IMHO</td>
<td>In My Humble Opinion</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>IMO</td>
<td>In My Opinion</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>LOL</td>
<td>Laughing Out Loud</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>OH</td>
<td>OverHeard</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>OTOH</td>
<td>On the Top Of my Head</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>POC</td>
<td>Person Of Color</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>PSA</td>
<td>Public Service Announcement</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>ROFL</td>
<td>Rolling On the Floor laughing</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>TFW</td>
<td>That Feeling When</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>TIA</td>
<td>Thanks In Advance</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>URM</td>
<td>UnderRepresented Minority</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>YOLO</td>
<td>You Only Live Once</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>See also this appropriate cartoon I found on Twitter:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet blockquote" data-lang="en">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">
How much do I love thee Tom Gould! <a href="https://t.co/yV5SPl6S84">pic.twitter.com/yV5SPl6S84</a>
</p>
— Lilian Edwards (<span class="citation" data-cites="lilianedwards">@lilianedwards</span>) <a href="https://twitter.com/lilianedwards/status/1039230031543889920?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 10, 2018</a>
</blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>



 ]]></description>
  <category>twitter</category>
  <guid>https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/2018-12-17-twitter-abbreviations/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Welcome to my new website!</title>
  <link>https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/2018-10-30-welcome/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p><img src="https://lexnederbragt.com/img/512px-Welcome_heading.svg.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>A while ago I decided that I wanted a website that</p>
<ul>
<li>I controlled by owning the domain</li>
<li>did not have any ads</li>
<li>was written in markdown</li>
<li>was under version control</li>
<li>allowed comments</li>
</ul>
<p>I looked around for templates and ended up using the one from Reproducible Research Oxford’s <a href="https://rroxford.github.io">website</a>, which based it on <a href="https://deanattali.com/beautiful-jekyll/">Beautiful Jekyll</a> (<a href="https://github.com/daattali/beautiful-jekyll">GitHub repo</a>).</p>
<p>I also did not want to lose old blog post from my blog over at <a href="http://flxlexblog.wordpress.com">wordpress.com</a>. I managed to add all those previous posts to this website, automatically forwarding the reader to their original location (I learned it is possible to export all posts from wordpress.com and import them into this site, and I may end up doing that, but it is a bit more work as I need to fix links to images etc).</p>
<p>So here it is: I own <a href="https://lexnederbragt.com">lexnederbragt.com</a>, and my blog is now at <a href="https://lexnederbragt.com/blog">lexnederbragt.com/blog</a>. The site is hosted on <a href="https://github.com/lexnederbragt/lexnederbragt.com/">GitHub</a> which allows me to write draft blog posts and ask for feedback before I publish them (by adding new posts in separate branches). In principle, others may submit fixes (typos, broken links) through GitHub also (we’ll see how eager people are to do that 😉).</p>
<p>I am opening for comments through Disqus, but this is an experiment, I may turn it off if discussions get off-topic, derailed or otherwise unpleasant. Check out the <a href="https://lexnederbragt.com/site_policy">site policy</a> before commenting!</p>
<p>I have one technical issue with the site, and that is that links from the tags from the blog posts do not lead to a page where all posts with that tag are listed (it works when I render the site locally on my laptop, but not on the live site). If anyone has a solution for that, I would appreciate <a href="https://github.com/lexnederbragt/lexnederbragt.com/issues/3">your input</a>.</p>
<p>(Image attribution: Sushiflinger <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0">CC BY-SA 3.0</a>, from <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Welcome_heading.svg">Wikimedia Commons</a>)</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>site</category>
  <guid>https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/2018-10-30-welcome/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Experiences with the first edition of “Introduction to Computational Modelling for the Biosciences”</title>
  <link>https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/2017-12-17-experiences-with-the-first-edition-of-introduction-to-computational-modelling-for-the-biosciences/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
<meta charset="utf-8">
<title>
Redirecting to the new site
</title>
<meta http-equiv="refresh" content="0; URL=https://flxlexblog.wordpress.com/2017/12/21/experiences-with-the-first-edition-of-introduction-to-computational-modelling-for-the-biosciences">
<p><link rel="canonical" href="https://flxlexblog.wordpress.com/2017/12/21/experiences-with-the-first-edition-of-introduction-to-computational-modelling-for-the-biosciences"></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>Teaching</category>
  <category>BIOS1100</category>
  <guid>https://lexnederbragt.com/blog/2017-12-17-experiences-with-the-first-edition-of-introduction-to-computational-modelling-for-the-biosciences/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
